

Profile

Thinking "out of the box" to provide software-based solutions

Software developer React/Node with strong skill in development and lifecycle management, over six years of experience as a full-stack developer, implementing best practices like test-driven development and introducing DevOps techniques such as continuous deployment, passionate about following agile methodologies and good practices like SOLID and DRY. Equally effective in a team environment or as alone specialist.

Employment History

Senior Full Stack Developer React/Node, at Encora

NOVEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

Philips (MSA): Software solution designed to analyze ECG data from patients using cardiac monitoring devices, such as MCOT (Mobile Cardiac Outpatient Telemetry) and similar devices. The system enables continuous monitoring and recording of cardiac events over extended periods, providing critical data for medical analysis and clinical decision-making.

- Angular
- Jasmine
- Java

Bio Telemetry Inc (Geneva): Monitor and generate reports for patients with implanted cardiac devices and relevant clinical histories. Responsible for implementing new functionalities and optimizing the application to enhance performance and usability.

- · React, Redux
- NodeJs
- Jest

Amazon (Transportation application): Carpool system. I was in charge of the base construction of the API and implementation of the project architecture, as well as the implementation of new functionalities. Main Skill performed in the project:

- AWS Amplify, Amazon Cognito, Dynamodb, CodePipile
- NodeJs
- Add security to API's
- Develop and support new features

Senior Full Stack Developer React/Node, at PSL

JULY 2017 - NOVEMBER 2020

Splunk: Single sign-on (SSO) using NodeJs and ReactJs

Xenial (Voice recognition system): The idea of this project is to take food orders by voice using the drive-thru and phone channels, we had big challenges like reducing background noise, knowing when the user stopped talking (VAD) and recognizing words that had similarities, we found great tools like Lex and DialogFlow that helped us with natural language understanding (NLU), voice activity detection (VAD) and Custom Recognition Intelligent Service (CRIS) that basically allow us to train a system with many examples of words that are vocally matched, all this process is done in real-time, all the code is written in Node and some GoLang

Details

Medellín

Colombia

3123512944

davin.anaya.s@gmail.com

Links

Linkedin

Skills

TypeScript

ReactJs

Jest

NodeJs

NestJs

AWS

MongoDB

DynamoDB

HTML5

CSS3

Scrum methodology

Kanban

Git

React Native

Languages

Spanish

English

Hatchbuck (CRM - Email Marketing): Implement React in the current system of the company since everything was built in jQuery and JavaScript, we started migrating small sections that did not affect the current system and were transparent to the user, and at the same time we executed new ideas and solved existing bugs

Junior - Mid software developer PHP/Javascript, at Arkis S.A

OCTOBER 2015 - JUNE 2017

- Websites with Reactjs and implemented React redux and router
- Landing pages with HTML, CSS3, Jquery and Javascript
- Research and implement scalable application identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval, and indexing
- Direct software design and development while remaining focused on client needs
- Collaborate closely with other team members to plan, design, and develop robust solution
- Technical support to determine optional specifications for Magento 2 and Drupal 7

Education

Technologist in information systems and development, SENA, Medellín

JANUARY 2011 - JANUARY 2014

English, Stafford House International, Toronto

OCTOBER 2016 - MAY 2017

Software Engineer, Universidad de San Buenaventura, Medellín

JULY 2020 - NOVEMBER 2024